In 2016,
the company Jusera from Silicon
Valley presented a revolutionary
home device.
A smart Wi-Fi juicer for $400
per unit.
But the most interesting part was
yet to come.
Juice was extracted only from
special branded packets with fruit
or vegetable puree,
which cost an additional $5-8
each.
In short,
just a juicer for the rich.
You insert the packet into it,
connect it to the internet,
and when you want,
you can press the button in
the app,
and it will make a fresh
juice.
Investors were thrilled.
A total of around $120 million
was invested in this project.
They set up production and put
this wonder-machine on sale.
Everything was fine until the day
X.
Journalists from the Bloomberg
publishing house bought one of the
packets with a preparation.
And you know what happened?
They simply squeezed the juice by
hand.
Here's a comparison of the juicer
and what they did without it.
It turned out that it can
be done not only faster,
but also no worse than through
the innovative device.
The internet exploded with memes.
Jusera became a symbol of absurd
gadgets for the rich.
Even Elon Musk joked that the
Silicon Valley juicer —
is the best proof that venture
funds are losing touch with
reality.
The company tried to justify
itself,
saying that the juicer regulates
pressure perfectly
and guarantees quality and taste.
But it was already too late.